Register of the Sybil Bailey Stockdale papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sybil Bailey Stockdale papers
1942-1997
Bulk, 1965-1973
81084
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes (5.2 linear feet)
Diaries, coorespondence, notes, press releases, clippings, photographs, and phonotapes, relating to American prisoners of war during the Vietnamese War and to their families.
Stockdale, Sybil Bailey
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Sybil Bailey Stockdale (1924-2015) was the wife of Vice Admiral James Bond Stockdale, United States Navy, and Prisoner of war in North Vietnam, 1965-1973. Stockdale was the National coordinator of the National League of Families of American Prisoners in Southeast Asia, and cowrote the memoir In Love and War: the Story of a Family's Ordeal and Sacrifice During the Vietnam War with her husband. James and Sybil both graduated with graduate degrees from Stanford University.
Scope and Contents note
The bulk of the collection contains correspondence between Sybil and James Stockdale from the begining of James' capture in Vietnam in 1965, till his release in 1973. The chronological file series maintains the original order of the creator; diaries, correspondence, notes, press releases, clippings, photographs, and phonotapes.
For itemized records within each year see the attached .pdf, or the "Inventory of documents: Sybil Stockdale Archives," located in box 2. Photographs have been removed and separated to box 13, in chronological order from where they appeared in the chronological file series.
National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia.; Navy spouses.; Prisoners of war.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Prisoners and prisons, North Vietnamese.
- Chronological file, 1965-1973
  Scope and Contents note
  Diaries, correspondence, notes, press releases, clippings, photographs, and phonotapes, relating to American prisoners of war during the Vietnamese War and to their families.
  See "Inventory of documents: Sybil Stockdale Archives," located in box 2, for itemized records within each year. Photographs have been removed and separated to box 13.
  - Inventory of documents, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Downloadable PDF file of "Inventory of documents: Sybil Stockdale Archives"
  - 1965 February - December (Box 2)
  - 1966 January - 1967 February (Box 3)
  - 1967 March - December (Box 4)
  - 1968 January - 1969 February (Box 5)
  - 1969 March - October (Box 6)
  - 1969 October - December (Box 7)
  - 1970 January - May (Box 8)
  - 1970 May - 1971 June (Box 9)
  - 1971 July - 1972 August (Box 10)
  - 1972 September - 1973 March (Box 11)
  - Newspaper, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Bridge and Bay Magazine, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - CBS News reel requests, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Letter received, Clark M. Gammel, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Department of Defense research materials, Circa 1970s (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - In Love and War: The Story of a Family's Ordeal and Sacrifice During the Vietnam Years book jackets, 1985 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Letter sent, MacLellan, 1989 (Box-folder 11: 14)
- Speeches and Writings
  - "Advise to potential prisoner of war families," speech, undated (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - "My brilliant career," speech, undated (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - "My philosophy about the prisoner of war studies," speech, undated (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - "NOW," speech, undated (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - James B. Stockdale, speech, to the Naval officers' wives club, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - James B. Stockdale, speech, Abingdon high school dedication, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - "1968 - What was changing," speech, circa 1997 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - Diary, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 11: 22)
    Annotated copy of original diary pages, the original entries occur within the collection, organized by date.
  - Manuscript duplicate, circa 1980s (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
- Miscellaneous
  - College scrapbook, 1942-1946 (Box 1)
  - POW Bracelet, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Darkness at Noon, Arthur Koestler, 1961 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Hospital visitation badge, 1973 (Box-folder 12: 5)
- Photographs, 1965-1970s
  - 1965 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - 1967 November (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Bob Dole, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - 1969 December (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - POW photographs, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - 1970 May (Box-folder 13: 6-8)
  - Family portraits, 1972 July, December (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Sybil Stockdale, portrait, circa 1970s (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Color, copy negatives, 1970 December (Box-folder 13: 11)
- Sound Recordings, 1970-1977
  - Sybil Stockdale, KFMB TV Show, 1970 February 12 (Cassette cabinet)
  - Sybil Stockdale, Dick Cavett Show, N.Y.C., 1972 July 4 (Cassette cabinet)
  - RAdm. James Stockdale, talk to Navy officer's wives, 1977 April 13 (Cassette cabinet)